<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/avocado/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/avocado/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-11T20:27:53+05:30</updated><id>/avocado/</id><title type="html">Avocado</title><subtitle>Avacado is a minimal theme to show off your skills online.</subtitle><author><name>John Doe</name></author><entry><title type="html">Love whatever you like!</title><link href="/avocado/blog/love-what-you-like/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Love whatever you like!" /><published>2017-09-05T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-09-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/avocado/blog/love-what-you-like</id><content type="html" xml:base="/avocado/blog/love-what-you-like/">&lt;p&gt;Campanula is one of several genera in the family Campanulaceae with the common name bellflower. It takes both its common and its scientific name from its bell-shaped flowers—campanula is Latin for “little bell”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The genus includes over 500 species and several subspecies, distributed across the temperate and subtropical regions of the Northern Hemisphere, with the highest diversity in the Mediterranean region east to the Caucasus. The range also extends into mountains in tropical regions of Asia and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;Learn more about this theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The species include annual, biennial and perennial plants, and vary in habit from dwarf arctic and alpine species under 5 cm high, to large temperate grassland and woodland species growing to 2 metres (6 ft 7 in) tall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaves are alternate and often vary in shape on a single plant, with larger, broader leaves at the base of the stem and smaller, narrower leaves higher up; the leaf margin may be either entire or serrated (sometimes both on the same plant). Many species contain white latex in the leaves and stems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flowers are produced in panicles (sometimes solitary), and have a five-lobed corolla, typically large (2–5 cm or more long), mostly blue to purple, sometimes white or pink. Below the corolla, 5 leaf-like sepals form the calyx. Some species have a small additional leaf-like growth termed an “appendage” between each sepal, and the presence or absence, relative size, and attitude of the appendage is often used to distinguish between closely related species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/avocado/images/800px-Campanula_flower_parts_text.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campanula species are used as food plants by the larvae of some Lepidoptera species including Common Pug (recorded on Harebell), Dot Moth, Ingrailed Clay (recorded on Harebell), Lime-speck Pug and Mouse Moth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cultivation-and-uses&quot;&gt;Cultivation and uses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well-known species include the northern temperate Campanula rotundifolia, commonly known as harebell in England and bluebell in Scotland and Ireland (though it is not closely related to the true bluebells), and the southern European Campanula medium, commonly known as Canterbury bells (a popular garden plant in the United Kingdom). As well as several species occurring naturally in the wild in northern Europe, there are many cultivated garden species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cultivars &lt;strong&gt;Burghaltii&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Kent Belle&lt;/strong&gt; have gained the Royal Horticultural Society’s Award of Garden Merit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The species Campanula rapunculus, commonly known as rampion bellflower, rampion, or rover bellflower, is a biennial vegetable which was once widely grown in Europe for its spinach-like leaves and radish-like roots. The Brothers Grimm’s tale Rapunzel took its name from this plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the UK the National Collection of campanulas is held at Burton Agnes Hall in East Yorkshire and the National Collection of Alpine Campanulas at Langham Hall in Suffolk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Campanula&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>john</name></author><summary type="html">Campanula is one of several genera in the family Campanulaceae with the common name bellflower. It takes both its common and its scientific name from its bell-shaped flowers—campanula is Latin for “little bell”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/avocado/round-leaved-bellflower-1576086_1280.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Do what you like!</title><link href="/avocado/blog/do-what-you-like/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do what you like!" /><published>2017-09-04T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-09-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/avocado/blog/do-what-you-like</id><content type="html" xml:base="/avocado/blog/do-what-you-like/">&lt;p&gt;Yoga is a group of physical, mental, and spiritual practices or disciplines which originated in ancient India. There is a broad variety of yoga schools, practices, and goals in Hinduism, Buddhism, and Jainism. Among the most well-known types of yoga are Hatha yoga and Rāja yoga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origins of yoga have been speculated to date back to pre-Vedic Indian traditions; it is mentioned in the Rigveda,[note 1] but most likely developed around the sixth and fifth centuries BCE, in ancient India’s ascetic and śramaṇa movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;Learn more about this theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chronology of earliest texts describing yoga-practices is unclear, varyingly credited to Hindu Upanishads. The Yoga Sutras of Patanjali date from the first half of the 1st millennium CE, but only gained prominence in the West in the 20th century. Hatha yoga texts emerged around the 11th century with origins in tantra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/avocado/images/meditation-2717462_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoga gurus from India later introduced yoga to the west, following the success of Swami Vivekananda in the late 19th and early 20th century. In the 1980s, yoga became popular as a system of physical exercise across the Western world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;etymology&quot;&gt;Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Sanskrit, the word yoga comes from the root yuj which means “to add”, “to join”, “to unite”, or “to attach” in its most common senses. By figurative extension from the yoking or harnessing of oxen or horses, the word took on broader meanings such as “employment, use, application, performance” (compare the figurative uses of “to harness” as in “to put something to some use”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All further developments of the sense of this word are post-Vedic. More prosaic moods such as “exertion”, “endeavour”, “zeal”, and “diligence” are also found in Indian epic poetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of Yoga is moksha (liberation), although the exact definition of what form this takes depends on the philosophical or theological system with which it is conjugated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Jacobsen, “Yoga has five principal meanings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoga, as a disciplined method for attaining a goal;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoga, as techniques of controlling the body and the mind;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoga, as a name of one of the schools or systems of philosophy (darśana);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoga, in connection with other words, such as “hatha-, mantra-, and laya-,” referring to traditions specialising in particular techniques of yoga;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoga, as the goal of Yoga practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yoga&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>john</name></author><summary type="html">Yoga is a group of physical, mental, and spiritual practices or disciplines which originated in ancient India. There is a broad variety of yoga schools, practices, and goals in Hinduism, Buddhism, and Jainism. Among the most well-known types of yoga are Hatha yoga and Rāja yoga.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/avocado/yoga-2662237_1280.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Go wherever you like!</title><link href="/avocado/blog/go-wherever-you-like/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Go wherever you like!" /><published>2017-09-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-09-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/avocado/blog/go-wherever-you-like</id><content type="html" xml:base="/avocado/blog/go-wherever-you-like/">&lt;p&gt;Goa (About this sound listen) is a state in India within the coastal region known as the Konkan in India. It is bounded by Maharashtra to the north and Karnataka to the east and south, with the Arabian Sea forming its Western coast. It is India’s smallest state by area and the fourth smallest by population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goa has the highest GDP per capita among all Indian states, that is two and a half times that of the country. It was ranked the best placed state by the “Eleventh Finance Commission” for its infrastructure and ranked on top for the best quality of life in India by the National Commission on Population based on the 12 Indicators&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;Learn more about this theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock art engravings found in Goa exhibit the earliest traces of human life in India.[8] Goa, situated within the Shimoga-Goa Greenstone Belt in the Western Ghats (an area composed of metavolcanics, iron formations and ferruginous quartzite), yields evidence for Acheulean occupation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flora-and-fauna&quot;&gt;Flora and fauna&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equatorial forest cover in Goa stands at 1,424 km2 (549.81 sq mi), most of which is owned by the government. Government owned forest is estimated at 1,224.38 km2 (472.74 sq mi) whilst private is given as 200 km2 (77.22 sq mi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the forests in the state are located in the interior eastern regions of the state. The Western Ghats, which form most of eastern Goa, have been internationally recognised as one of the biodiversity hotspots of the world. In the February 1999 issue of National Geographic Magazine, Goa was compared with the Amazon and the Congo basins for its rich tropical biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tourism&quot;&gt;Tourism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tourism is generally focused on the coastal areas of Goa, with decreased tourist activity inland. In 2010, there were more than two million tourists reported to have visited Goa, about 1.2 million of whom were from abroad. As of 2013 Goa was a destination of choice for Indian and foreign tourists, particularly Britons and Russians, with limited means who wanted to party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/avocado/images/travel-2614857_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state was hopeful that changes could be made which would attract a more upscale demographic. Goa also stands 6th in the Top 10 Nightlife cities in the world in a National Geographic Book. One of the biggest tourist attractions in Goa is water sports. Beaches like Baga and Calangute offer jet-skiing, parasailing, banana boat rides, water scooter rides and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>john</name></author><summary type="html">Goa (About this sound listen) is a state in India within the coastal region known as the Konkan in India. It is bounded by Maharashtra to the north and Karnataka to the east and south, with the Arabian Sea forming its Western coast. It is India’s smallest state by area and the fourth smallest by population.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/avocado/sunglasses-2523803_1280.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learn whatever you want!</title><link href="/avocado/blog/learn-whatever-you-want/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learn whatever you want!" /><published>2017-09-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-09-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/avocado/blog/learn-whatever-you-want</id><content type="html" xml:base="/avocado/blog/learn-whatever-you-want/">&lt;p&gt;Learning is the act of acquiring new or modifying and reinforcing existing knowledge, behaviors, skills, values, or preferences which may lead to a potential change in synthesizing information, depth of the knowledge, attitude or behavior relative to the type and range of experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to learn is possessed by humans, animals, plants and some machines. Progress over time tends to follow a learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;Learn more about this theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning does not happen all at once, but it builds upon and is shaped by previous knowledge. To that end, learning may be viewed as a process, rather than a collection of factual and procedural knowledge. Learning produces changes in the organism and the changes produced are relatively permanent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;types&quot;&gt;Types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;non-associative-learning&quot;&gt;Non-associative learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-associative learning refers to “a relatively permanent change in the strength of response to a single stimulus due to repeated exposure to that stimulus. Changes due to such factors as sensory adaptation, fatigue, or injury do not qualify as non-associative learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;active-learning&quot;&gt;Active learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active learning occurs when a person takes control of his/her learning experience. Since understanding information is the key aspect of learning, it is important for learners to recognize what they understand and what they do not. By doing so, they can monitor their own mastery of subjects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/avocado/images/boys-1782427_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active learning encourages learners to have an internal dialogue in which they verbalize understandings. This and other meta-cognitive strategies can be taught to a child over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies within metacognition have proven the value in active learning, claiming that the learning is usually at a stronger level as a result. In addition, learners have more incentive to learn when they have control over not only how they learn but also what they learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active learning is a key characteristic of student-centered learning. Conversely, passive learning and direct instruction are characteristics of teacher-centered learning (or traditional education).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>john</name></author><summary type="html">Learning is the act of acquiring new or modifying and reinforcing existing knowledge, behaviors, skills, values, or preferences which may lead to a potential change in synthesizing information, depth of the knowledge, attitude or behavior relative to the type and range of experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/avocado/coffee-2306471_1280.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Be what you want to be!</title><link href="/avocado/blog/be-what-you-want-to-be/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be what you want to be!" /><published>2017-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/avocado/blog/be-what-you-want-to-be</id><content type="html" xml:base="/avocado/blog/be-what-you-want-to-be/">&lt;p&gt;As in other arts, the definitions of amateur and professional are not entirely categorical. A professional photographer is likely to take photographs to make money, by salary or through the display, sale or use of those photographs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An amateur photographer may take photographs for pleasure and to record an event, emotion, place, as a person without a monetary motivation. A professional photographer may be an employee, for example of a newspaper, or may contract to cover a particular planned event such as a wedding or graduation, or to illustrate an advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;Learn more about this theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;selling-photographs&quot;&gt;Selling photographs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exclusive right of photographers to copy and use their products is protected by copyright. Countless industries purchase photographs for use in publications and on products. The photographs seen on magazine covers, in television advertising, on greeting cards or calendars, on websites, or on products and packages, have generally been purchased for this use, either directly from the photographer or through an agency that represents the photographer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/avocado/images/hipster-865295_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A photographer uses a contract to sell the “license” or use of his or her photograph with exact controls regarding how often the photograph will be used, in what territory it will be used (for example U.S. or U.K. or other), and exactly for which products. This is usually referred to as usage fee and is used to distinguish from production fees (payment for the actual creation of a photograph or photographs). An additional contract and royalty would apply for each additional use of the photograph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;photo-sharing&quot;&gt;Photo sharing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people upload their photographs to social networking websites and other websites, in order to share them with a particular group or with the general public. Those interested in legal precision may explicitly release them to the public domain or under a free content license. Some sites, including Wikimedia Commons, are punctilious about licenses and only accept pictures with clear information about permitted use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photographer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>john</name></author><summary type="html">As in other arts, the definitions of amateur and professional are not entirely categorical. A professional photographer is likely to take photographs to make money, by salary or through the display, sale or use of those photographs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/avocado/beautiful-2150881_1280.jpg" /></entry></feed>